## YOFETAHE S. HABTU

(206) 887 6266 US Permanent Residence (Green-Card Holder)

yofetahe.h@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/yofetahe-habtu/ | https://github.com/yofetahe | https://www.yofetahe.com/

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Full stack developer with 4+ years of web-based application development experience. Proactive learner, continuously improving skills and researching leading-edge tools to ensure relevant knowledge within constantly changing IT landscape. Determined to contribute value to the group or project I am working on. Work with my colleagues collaboratively to result in unified applications.

#### **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

Languages: Java, C#, Python, JavaScript, Typescript, HTML,

CSS. SQL

Web Technology: AJAX, JSP, Socket.io, Node.js

**Databases**: Oracle, MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server, MongoDB **Frameworks**: Spring, Hibernate, JPA, Angular, React with Redux, MVC .NET, Entity Framework, Express.js, Flask,

Django, Bootstrap, Materialize

Tools: Eclipse/STS, MS Visual Studio, IntelliJ, NetBeans

Cloud Platform: Pivotal Cloud Foundry, AWS

Methodology: OOP, MVC, Agile Platforms: Windows, Mac OS

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# Technology Analyst, Infosys Technologies (Client Microsoft) - WA, USA

February 2020 till Present

- Create, update and debug connectors (a layer between APIs and front-end) for Microsoft Store Application.
- Involve in system dev spec document preparation for new connectors together with business analysts.
- Add and update system documentation.

### Software Engineer, HCL Technologies - WA, USA

June 2019 to January 2020

- Shadow senior software engineers on the front-end features developments using React, React-hook and React-Context and backend functionality development using Java, spring boot, and hibernate.
- Participate in in-house project development on the back end development using java and spring boot.
- Develop front end (JavaScript, React, Angular and CSS) and backend technologies (Java, C# and Node.js) and also deploy
  applications on Cloud Infrastructure (Cloud Foundry, Azure and AWS) and develop personal project (commercial site using
  React, Java and MySQL) and deploy on cloud foundry.

### Software Engineer, YamGet IT Solutions Plc - Addis Ababa, ETH

March 2015 to April 2018

- Develop four projects' (Fright, School, Human Resource and Building Management System) backend using Java technologies such as Spring, Spring MVC, Spring boot, Hibernate and frontend using JSP and React with Redux.
- Develop two projects' (Medical Service License Management System and Document Flow Management System) backend using C# technologies such as ASP.MVC 4, Entity Framework and front end using Angular with TypeScript.
- Enhance SQL queries of existing applications for a better performance
- Facilitated customization of best practices to adopt emerging standards for application development architecture and tools.
- Participated in project presentations to end users and managers to make the software solutions easy-to-understand.
- Help on major deals by generating well formatted and easy to understand project presentation documents for the applications.
- Research, design, develop and implement scalable applications for clients

## Software Engineer, Apposit LLC - Addis Ababa, ETH

April 2014 - March 2015

- Change business logic implementation and fix bugs on the existing system
- Develop new features as per end users request using Java, Spring Core and Hibernate
- Work on the back-end development of application enhancement to a new version
- Develop new sub project based on requirement document when a new firm join the platform using Groovy and Grails

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Science in Management Information System**

September 2005 – August 2009

- Micro-Link Information Technology College, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia
- **Coursework:** Object-Oriented Programming · Windows Programming · Front End Programming · Database Management Systems · Software Project Management · Information Systems · Networking · System Analysis & Design

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

CFCD: Cloud Foundry Certified Developer, By Linux Foundation

Certificate ID Number: CFCD-1900-0579-0200

Issued August 2015

Issued Dec 2019

OCP: Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 6 Programmer, By Oracle

Certificate ID Number: 2260944270CPJSE6P

January - April, 2019

Full Stack Development Certificate, Coding Dojo, Bellevue USA

amework)				